# Patrick Reagan

patrick@the-reagans.com / github.com/reagent / patrick-reagan.com ph: 703.303.7977

# Summary

I am an experienced, pragmatic software developer with a love for code quality, collaboration, and continuous improvement. I excel at breaking down complex engineering problems and building applications that deliver value across a diverse set of business domains.

## **Experience**

#### KindHealth - Principal Engineer

February 2021 - Present

At KindHealth, I build technology solutions that help scale our growing brokerage business.

- Reworked critical pieces of our PostgreSQL database schema which improved data integrity and allowed us to capture more commission revenue
- Simplified operational complexity by migrating from a SQS / serverless setup to a proven Redis-backed queuing solution that provided better resilience at our smaller scale
- Improved the stability of our core platform through the addition of an integration test layer which allowed the team to more quickly develop features and squash bugs
- Built a shared data access library that provided a migration pathway away from an untested legacy Express / JavaScript backend towards a modern Nest.js / TypeScript backend
- Fostered an engineering culture of constant improvement through thoughtful code reviews, tech-focused presentations, and one-on-one remote pairing sessions with other engineers

## Gloo, LLC - Staff Engineer: Platform

November 2019 - January 2021

As Staff Engineer, I architected and built several HTTP-based microservices in support of various in-market applications.

- Improved the quality and delivery of a variety of TypeScript microservices through better API design, thorough testing, and meaningful code reviews
- Helped scale an existing Rails API by directing database reads to be performed against our read-only Aurora replica to handle unique traffic spikes
- Led bi-weekly meetings that provided a venue for engineers to share best practices for application development, demonstrate platform observability features, and keep the team up-to-date on relevant technologies
- Coordinated and directed contractor teams in assisting with feature planning and bug fixes for critical inmarket products and supporting microservices

# **Viget Labs, LLC - Development Director**

June 2005 - November 2019

In addition to my work developing applications for a variety of clients, I also:

- Helped grow the company's presence in Boulder from a single person co-working outpost into a fullfledged office
- Created and refined our engineering hiring process in order to provide consistency in evaluation and ensure that only the top candidates were considered for in-person evaluations
- Established, planned, and led the engineering team's bi-annual offsite meetings as a means to connect personally and improve professionally
- Improved software delivery by introducing agile methods that included iteration planning, acceptance testdriven development, and iteration retrospectives

#### Viget Labs, LLC - Applications Technologist

November 2000 - June 2005

- Administered internal and client servers running a variety of operating systems, web servers, and databases
- Developed custom database-backed web applications for clients using a variety of languages, databases, and deployment configurations
- Provided technical leadership in the areas of payment systems integration and application performance
- Advocated and implemented development standards that included the use of version control, API documentation, and automated unit and integration testing
- Developed a reusable MVC framework written in PHP that streamlined the application development process

#### **Selected Client Work**

- 2018 2019 Modernized the ticket purchasing experience for visitors to the **Shedd Aquarium** website by providing a deep integration with their existing ticketing software (*Ruby, Rails, PostgreSQL, API Integration*)
- 2017 2018 Worked closely with the web team at **Bethesda Softworks** to re-platform microsites for their popular game titles (Fallout / Elder Scrolls / Quake) using a custom-built PHP library to fetch content from the Contentful API in time for a major E3 announcement (PHP, Laravel, API Integration)
- 2016 2017 Launched the new "Best States" microsite for **US News** which allowed users to perform multi-faceted rankings comparisons between US states with data delivered from a major publisher as flat files (*Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Custom API*)
- 2012 2015 Re-platformed the main **Shure** North America web presence which improved product promotion and provided better integration of custom tools (*Ruby*, *Rails*, *MySQL*, *Redis*, *API Integration*)

# **Selected Software Projects**

- Fleakr (Ruby) A full-featured API client for Flickr photostreams
- dnsimple (Python) Re-imagining improved ergonomics for interacting with the DNSimple API
- minecraft-server (Ansible / Python) Simplifying setup and teardown of family Minecraft servers

#### **Publications**

Advanced Rails Recipes / Pragmatic Bookshelf / 2009 (Contributing Author)

A Practical Guide to WinCVS and SSH / CvsGui Project / 2002

Using Oracle With PHP / WebMonkey (Wired Digital) / 2001

### **Presentations**

Coding with Confidence: Adding TDD to Your Toolset / CMAP Fall Code Camp / 2009

Effective Testing for Rails Projects / Ruby Hack Day / 2009

Make Everyone a Tester: Natural Language Acceptance Testing / Developer Day DC & CVREG /

2009

Changing Your Mindset: Getting Started with Test-Driven Development / Lone Star Ruby Conference / 2007

Mockfight! Flexmock v. Mocha / NovaRUG / 2007

#### **Education**

James Madison University B.S. Computer Science (1999)